Guide to the Time Inc. Life Editorial Records 1937-2013 MS 3009-RG 9
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. John Loengard Interview Project Videotapes [RESTRICTED], 1992-2005; 231851; 4 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
  - Davis, Myron?, 231880 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 17-20)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Davis Interview 10/28/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Davis Interview 10/28/93."
  - Dean, Loomis, 231879 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 21-24)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Dean Interview 11/4/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Dean Interview 11/4/93."
  - Feininger, Andreas, 231878 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 25-28)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Feininger Interview (1/13/92)."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Copy from the Time Inc. Archives. The Research Center, Time Inc. Feininger Interview (1/13/92)."
  - Fenn, Albert, 231877 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 29-30)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Fenn Interview 10/22/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Fenn Interview 10/22/93."
  - Grant, Allan, 231876 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 31)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Grant Interview 8/12/92."
  - Groskinsky, Henry, 231875 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 32-33)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Groskinsky Interview 10/20/93."
  - Groskinsky, Henry, 231960 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 1-2)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Groskinsky Interview 10/20/93."
  - Hardy, Rex?, 231874 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 3-4)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Hardy Interview 8/15/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Hardy Interview 8/15/93."
  - Holmes, Martha?, 231961 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 5)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Holmes Interview 5/18/93."
  - Joel, Yale, 231873 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 6-9)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Joel Interview 5/20/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Joel Interview 5/20/93."
  - Kauffman, Mark, 231872 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 10-13)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Kauffman Interview 8/13/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Kauffman Interview 8/13/93."
  - Kessel, Dmitri, 231871 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 14-17)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Kessel Interview (9/20/93)."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Kessel Interview (9/20/93)."
  - Lane, Walter?, 231870 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 18-19)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Lane Interview 10/26/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Lane Interview 10/26/93."
  - Leen, Nina, 232002 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 20)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. N. Leen Interview 1/14/92."
  - Linck, Tony, 231869 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 21-22)
    1 videocassete (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Linck Interview 10/25/93."
    1 videocassete (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Linck Interview 10/25/93."
  - Loengard, John, 231868 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 23-24)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Loengard Interview 5/22/93."
  - Mauney, Michael, 231867 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 25-26)
    1 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Mauney Interview 10/26/93."
    1 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Mauney Interview 10/26/93."
  - Merrit, Vernon, III, 231866 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 27-28)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. Time Inc. Archives. The Research Center, Time Inc. Merrit Interview 10/27/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Merrit Interview 10/27/93."
  - Mieth, Hansel, 232004 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 29-30)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Mieth Interview 8/15/93."
  - Morse, Ralph, 231865 (Offsite-box 2198, Item 31-32)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Morse Interview 9/30/94."
  - Morse, Ralph, 232006 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 1-2)
  - Mydans, Carl, 232007 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 3-5)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Mydans Interview (1/9/92)."
  - Olson, John?, 231864 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 6-7)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Olson Interview 10/29/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Olson Interview 10/29/93."
  - Parks, Gordon, 232011 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 8-9)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Copy from Time Inc. Archives. The Research Center, Time Inc. Parks Interview 5/18/93."
  - Phillips, John, 231863 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 10-13)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Phillips Interview 5/19/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Phillips Interview 5/19/93."
  - Preston, Hart, 231862 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 14-15)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Preston Interview 8/13/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Preston Interview 8/13/93."
  - Ray, Bill?, 231861 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 16-17)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Ray Interview 10/26/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Ray Interview 10/26/93."
  - Rentmeester, Co, 231860 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 18-21)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Rentmeester Interview 5/19/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Rentmeester Interview 5/19/93."
  - Scherman, Rowland?, 232012 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 22)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Scherman Interview 5/20/93. Tape 2 of 2."
    Tape 1 of 1 is currently missing.
  - Scherschel, Frank, 231859 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 23-24)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Scherschel Interview 10/22/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Scherschel Interview 10/22/93."
  - Shearer, John, 232015 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 25-26)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Shearer Interview 10/20/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Shearer Interview 10/20/93."
  - Silk, George, 231858 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 27-30)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Silk Interview 5/21/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Silk Interview 5/21/93."
  - Sochurek, Howard, 231857 (Offsite-box 2199, Item 31-32)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Sochurek Interview 10/28/93."
  - Sochurek, Howard, 232020 (Offsite-box 2200, Item 1-2)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Sochurek Interview 10/28/93."
  - Stackpole, Peter, 231856 (Offsite-box 2200, Item 3-6)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Stackpole Interview 8/16/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Stackpole Interview 8/16/93."
  - Steinheimer, Charles, 231855 (Offsite-box 2200, Item 7-8)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Steinheimer Interview 8/16/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Steinheimer Interview 8/16/93."
  - Sumits, William J., 231854 (Offsite-box 2200, Item 9-10)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Summits Interview 10/27/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Summits Interview 10/27/93."
  - Villet, Grey, 231853 (Offsite-box 2200, Item 11-12)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Villet Interview 10/29/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Villet Interview 10/29/93."
  - Walker, Hank, 231852 (Offsite-box 2200, Item 13-16)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Walker Interview 9/29/94."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Walker Interview 9/29/94."
- Series X. Book Copy Files: LIFE: The Greatest Adventures of All Time, circa 2000; 3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  According to the Time Inc. archivist, Life began publishing more books showcasing the photograph collection around the time the monthly magazine closed in 2000. Robert Sullivan was named a senior editor at Life in 1994 and later became the assistant managing editor of the monthly Life. A 2004 staff memo in his bio file (MS 3009-RG 2) states that Sullivan was running the editorial side of books published under the Life imprint.
  Hooper, Bill. Email to Holly Deakyne, 24 September 2019.
  These copy files are from the book LIFE: The Greatest Adventures of All Time published by Life in 2001. The copy files include emails and notes from editor Robert Sullivan, writer and researcher Catherine Buni, and fact checkers Anne Hollister, Lela Nargi, and Deirdre van Dyk. The records include research, galleys, photocopies of images to be used, possibly new interviews with water explorers Robert Ballard and Sylvia Earle conducted by K. Wroth, and a small amount of correspondence from water explorer Thor Heyerdahl.
  Organized into book front matter and maps followed by chapters/explorers. The explorers are organized by terrain of exploration then alphabetically by name. A published copy of the book was not available so the files could not be arranged by chapter of the book.
  - Front Matter and Maps, circa 2000 (Offsite-box 3410)
  - Chapters/Explorers: Air, circa 2000 (Offsite-box 3410)
  - Chapters/Explorers: Air-Land, circa 2000 (Offsite-box 3411)
  - Chapters/Explorers: Land-Water, circa 2000 (Offsite-box 3412)